Brice Shatzer

www.BriceShatzer.com

brice.shatzer@gmail.com 319-239-2470

Chicago-based technologist with a decade of experience successfully building software for businesses of all sizes. While I specialize in crafting novel user-facing interactions, I have a deep passion for the administrative and organizational processes around the craft of software development.

Tools & Technologies

- React
- Node.js + Express.js
- Flow / TypeScript
- Webpack & Babel
- Git / Mercurial / SVN
- styled-components
- SASS / LESS

- "Vanilla" HTML,
 CSS, & Javascript
- Backbone.js + Marionette
- Vue.is
- Jest, Mocha, Jasmine,
 Enzyme, Puppeteer, & Karma
- Grunt / Gulp

- AWS Lambda
- Apache / NGINX
- PHP
 - Laravel
 - CraftCMS
 - WordPress

Recent Work Experience

Senior Software Engineer — PayPal

July 2020 - August 2021

- Part of the Checkout Integrations team that worked on the company's flagship Checkout product handling \$100+B in payment volume across 200+ countries for millions of active users a month
- Primary developer and point of contact for our "Pay w/ Venmo" desktop solution, enabling users to generate a QR Code that allows them to complete the checkout process via their mobile device
- Generated & updated documentation around the various tools and libraries that are used both internally and made available to the open source community

Software Engineer — Onion Inc. | G/O Media

September 2017 - April 2020

- Part of the team that worked on Kinja, the CMS powering some of the internet's favorite sites like Gizmodo, Lifehacker, Kotaku, and The Onion; reaching 85-100 million active users a month
- Helped migrate and rewrite our core platform from a Scala w/ Closure templates back-end & Backbone + Marionette front-end to Isomorphic JavaScript (Express & React)

Full Work History

Software Engineer

February 2016 - April 2017

 $\label{eq:Doejo} \mbox{Doejo} - \mbox{Digital agency that specialized in serving enterprise WordPrss VIP clients}$

Web Developer II

September 2015 - February 2016

GoHealth — One of the leading digital health insurance marketplaces

UI/Front-End Developer

November 2014 - September 2015

Packback — SharkTank-funded startup creating a platform for digital textbook rentals

Web Developer

August 2014 - July 2015

Freelance — Clients: LiveOneGroups.com, Legal-Lease.com, PACOcollective.com

Web Developer/Designer

April 2012 - July 2014

Links Technology Solutions — Agency providing custom web & software solutions

Education